Previously on Kaiju No. 8.
《怪兽8号》前情提要
What is that? What the hell is going on?
怎么回事？发生什么事了？
The dead kaiju are reacting. They're coming back to life.
应该死掉的怪兽又出现反应了
You did well, Kikoru!
你很努力了呢，琪歌露！
I don't have time right now. I'll clean you up…
我赶时间，看我一拳…
in one blow!
把你解体！
Despite the unexpected incident, Senpai's final exam came to an end.
尽管发生意料之外的事件 前辈依然顺利完成最终测验
It's all because you pushed me to keep going.
多亏有你在背后推一把
Thanks, Ichikawa.
谢谢你，市川
After overcoming this challenge,
克服困难之后
Senpai seemed even more reliable than before.
前辈看起来更加可靠了
I can't!
绝对不会过啦！
Nope. Never mind.
看来只是错觉
It's too scary! Way too scary!
好可怕哦！
It's your fault!
都是你的错啦！
It's your fault for pushing me!
都怪你推了我一把
That's why I'm so afraid now!
才害我有这么惨痛的经验！
You thanked me at the hospital!
在医院的时候你明明很感谢我
What happened to that wise, philosophical Senpai?
当时那个豁达的前辈去哪里了？
Kafka, Ichikawa!
卡夫卡、市川
These letters arrived for you.
你们的信来了哦
ORIGINAL WORK BY NAOYA MATSUMOTO
（原作：松本直也）
NEUTRALIZATION BUREAU
（讨伐厅）
All right. Let's open on three.
好，数到三就打开
There's no way around this. This is my last chance.
不管是哭是笑，这都是最后一次了
Will my path lead to me standing next to her?
我的道路是否能延伸到她身边呢？
Now's the time to know!
就看这次了
One, two…
一、二…
DEAR KAFKA HIBINO SELECTION RESULTS
（致日比野卡夫卡：选拔结果通知）
Hey. I knew you had passed.
哟，就知道你会考过
Same to you.
你也是啊
Most of the people are just as I expected.
几乎跟我预料的一样
Shinomiya's stalker fan isn't here.
要追四之宫的那家伙不在呢
-Did you want him to pass? -No, I thought…
-你希望他考过吗？ -不，我…
It's Shinomiya!
喂，是四之宫
Shinomiya-san! I heard you earned the top score!
四之宫小姐，我听说了，你是榜首呢
Yup. They asked me to do the oath.
对啊，还要当宣誓代表
-Excited to work with you! -Same here.
-请多指教咯 -请多指教
Before the application process, I thought I'd get the top score.
在考试前，我还以为榜首会是我呢
But after all that she did, it's obvious.
毕竟她表现得很出色
Let's fight for the Number Two position, shall we?
我们要不要争第二名啊？
I was first in the physical fitness score.
我的体力测验是第一名哦
You aim for Number Two, I'll aim for the top.
你的目标是第二，我的目标是第一
Oh, sorry. Hey, I know you.
噢，对不起，你…
You're that old man's partner.
我记得你是那个大叔的同伴
I'm Reno Ichikawa.
我叫市川雷诺
Sorry. I'm bad at remembering names.
抱歉，我很不会记名字
I'm Iharu Furuhashi.
我叫古桥伊春
Nice to meet you, Furuhashi-san.
请多指教，古桥先生
Just call me Iharu, Reno!
叫我伊春就好了，雷诺
All right, then.
好…
Where's the old man? He didn't make it?
大叔呢？他没录取吗？
Well, Senpai…
前辈他…
Captain Mina Ashiro is entering!
亚白米娜队长，入场！
Captain Ashiro.
亚白队长
She's finally here!
终于来了
The ceremony will commence.
颁发入队证书
Top accepted applicant, Kikoru Shinomiya.
防卫队录取者代表，四之宫琪歌露
Yes!
是！
Starting today, the 27 of you
今天起，任命你们27人
will be appointed as Defense Force officers.
成为防卫队队员
As the representative of the 27 new members,
我代表27人立誓
I swear on my life to fight for the Defense Force!
将拼上性命战斗
You helped us greatly with the incident after the exams.
你在测验后的事件帮了很大的忙
Thanks to you, there were no victims.
多亏了你，才没有出现被害者
I thank you once again.
再次向你郑重感谢
I didn't defeat the kaiju.
打到怪兽的不是我
Kafka Hibino,
日比野卡夫卡
you should be receiving these words right now.
这句感谢应该由你收下才对
Why aren't you here?
为什么你却不在这里？
Not only did he save me, but he expressed concern for me,
竟然敢在救了我之后
as if he was above me.
还自以为是地担心我
I'm glad you're okay!
幸好你没事
How humiliating!
真是屈辱！
I need to interrogate him about his kaiju form.
我还想问清楚他变身成怪兽的事情
I won't forgive him if I never see him again.
绝不允许他就此消失在我面前
Excuse me?
不好意思
Sorry for coming in during the middle of the ceremony.
进行到一半才来，对不起
What's going on?
怎么了？
Old man?
大叔？
Number 2032, Kafka Hibino, will be rejected.
2032号，日比野卡夫卡，不合格
He's on the lowest rank for physical fitness,
体力测验的等级最低
and his suit compatibility is currently zero. It can't be helped.
目前对战斗服的适应性为零 这也没办法
Yeah, that's what I figured.
嗯，那就这样吧
-So, no objections? -I'll object.
-没有异… -那交给我吧
It's true that his performance was below average.
他的成绩确实低于平均
He should be rejected as an officer.
不足以成为防卫队员
But he was able to find the enemy's weak points during the final test,
不过他在最终测验的实战中 找出敌人的弱点
prioritized supporting others rather than his own score,
比起自己的分数，更优先支援其他人
and contributed greatly.
为讨伐做出贡献
That's not something anyone can do.
这可不是谁都做得到的
And finally,
更重要的是
he made a great contribution as the team's comedian.
他身为搞笑专员的表现十分出色
I knew it!
我就知道！
I don't know if he could get promoted as an officer yet,
虽然不确定他能否升格为正式队员
but I'll train him as a cadet in my platoon.
他就作为候补队员 在我的小队重新锻炼吧
He will be joining the Force as a cadet,
他是以候补的身份加入
so he was not part of the officer swearing-in.
所以没有让他参加任命仪式
That's more like it, Kafka Hibino.
这样才对嘛，日比野卡夫卡
I knew he had passed.
他果然也合格了
-Even though he's a cadet. -That was unexpected.
-虽然是候补 -真是出乎意料
Now that everyone's here,
这样就全员到齐了
Captain Ashiro will say a few words.
请亚白队长致辞
Hello, all. First of all, I'm very happy that you applied to the Defense Force,
各位，首先 对于你们志愿加入防卫队
stuck through the difficult application process, and passed.
通过严格的测验并且合格 我觉得十分高兴
I thank you all.
感谢你们
Recently, the number of kaiju appearances
最近，怪兽的出现次数
and their fortitudes
以及规模
have both increased much higher than the historical average.
都远高于历年的平均值
There was also the mysterious incident of dead kaiju coming back to life.
甚至还发生死去的怪兽复活的怪事
You will experience many dangerous and life-threatening neutralizations.
想必未来与死相伴的 危险讨伐会只增不减
Some may die on their first mission.
说不定第一个任务就会有人殉职
We cannot guarantee your life in the slightest.
你们的性命没有任何保障
But even then, or perhaps because of those reasons,
即使如此，正因为这样
we want you to entrust your life with us.
我希望你们把性命借给我
I promise to be at the front line, becoming your shield
我发誓会站在最前线，成为你们的盾
and your spear.
还有矛
And I'll stand next to you in no time, Mina!
我也很快…就会站到你身边的，米娜
WHAT!?
（欸？）
HUH!?
（什么？）
CHILLY AIR
（冷风飕飕）
-What's wrong with him? -He's insane!
-这家伙是怎样？ -太夸张了
He called Captain Ashiro by her first name!
他竟然直呼亚白队长的名字！
OOPS
（啊）
Kaf…
卡…
Kafka Hibino. Speaking without permission. Addressing a superior by first name.
日比野卡夫卡 未经许可发言，直呼长官姓名
Hundred pushups in total.
俯卧撑一百下
Shit, I didn't mean to say that out loud!
该死，不小心把内心话说出来了！
On his first day, too!
马上就闯祸了
You're being too lenient, Captain Ashiro.
这点惩罚会不会太轻了，亚白队长？
Was she smiling just now?
她刚刚是不是笑了？
Looks like Vice-Captain's hired comedian is already at work.
马上就发挥作用了呢 副队长的搞笑专员
Right? I knew he had potential!
对吧？就跟我计划的一样
This job can get dark.
这工作不是很沉重吗？
I think guys like that are important.
我认为有这种人很重要呢
Though that's only half the truth.
虽然有一半是借口
During the kaiju resurrections,
怪兽陆续复活时
a fortitude 9.8 reading suddenly appeared.
突然出现怪兽规模9.8的反应
It's probably an error, but someone's vitals disappeared at the same time.
虽然觉得是仪器异常 但同时有个人的生命体征消失了
Kafka Hibino. Along with his abnormally low compatibility with the suit,
日比野卡夫卡 对战斗服的适应性也异常地低
there are a lot of strange things about him.
这个人有哪里不太对劲
I'll keep him close to him to figure out what this strangeness is.
得把他放在身边 查明这些疑点的真相
Ninety-nine… 100!
99…100！
You did well, old man!
大叔，干得好！
Kafka Hibino.
日比野卡夫卡
Come. I need to talk to you.
过来，我有话跟你说
What is it? We can't talk here?
干嘛？不能在这里讲吗？
-Not here. -Is it a confession of love?
-这里的话… -难道是要告白？
No, it isn't!
不是啦！
-Senpai. -I know what this is.
-前辈 -是那个吧？
She's challenging me to a duel.
去体育馆单挑之类的
Just come already!
过来就是了！
What?
什么？
You ate a kaiju and became one yourself?
你吃了怪兽，就变成怪兽了？
I can't believe it! You were that hungry?
真不敢相信，你有那么饿吗？
-I didn't eat it on purpose! -Both of you, keep your voices down.
-我又不是自愿吃的！ -你们两个太大声了！
Maybe I should just tell the Defense Force.
我也想过要不要跟防卫队坦白
Maybe they could cure me.
搞不好有办法治好
-That's impossible. -What?
-最好不要 -咦？
Even if they don't kill you,
就算你没被处分
they'd do tests and experiments on you nonstop.
也得每天接受检查和实验
You'll never have a future as a Defense Officer.
你的防卫队员生涯会就此结束
Really?
是哦？
Also, kaiju that are strong enough to be assigned a number
而且冠上代号的强力怪兽
are used as parts for a special weapon after they're taken down.
在被打倒后，通常都会 用来当作特殊武器的零件
Worst case scenario, that'll happen to you.
最糟的情况，你也会如此
Please, Kikoru!
琪歌露，拜托你
Please keep this a secret between us!
请把这件事当作我们的秘密
Please save this old man's life!
救救我一个可怜的大叔！
-You're too close! -Please, please!
-太近了！ -求求你！
Fine. You did save me.
知道了啦，你都救了我一命
I'll keep it quiet for now.
我就暂时帮你保密
However,
相对的
if I ever find out that you're a danger to humans,
如果我知道你是有害人类的怪兽
I'll kill you.
我就会杀了你
Yeah.
嗯
I'm counting on you if that time comes.
到时就拜托你了
NEUTRALIZATION BUREAU
（讨伐厅）
Tuck my elbows and relax my wrist.
手臂贴紧，手腕放松
Trust your senses when capturing the reticle. And don't pull the trigger,
凭感觉移动准星 锁定目标，不是扣下扳机
squeeze!
而是勒紧！
Squeeze.
勒紧
Shooting training for Reno Ichikawa is complete.
市川雷诺，射击训练结束
Time is two minutes 35 seconds.
花费时间2分35秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 18%.
推定解放战力，18%
Haruichi-kun! I have a question!
阳一，我想问你问题
Growing this much in such a short amount of time is incredible.
这么短的时间进步这么多 有点惊人呢
That Reno, he improved his score again!
雷诺那小子，战力又提升了
Bring it on!
上啊！
Like I'd lose to him!
怎么能输给他？
Iharu Furuhashi, two minutes 15 seconds.
古桥伊春，2分15秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 20%.
推定解放战力，20%
All right!
很好
I won, Reno! Don't underestimate me!
我赢了，可别得意忘形了，雷诺
I never did.
我才没有
Kikoru Shinomiya, one minute 16 seconds.
四之宫琪歌露，1分16秒
Estimated unleashed combat power, 55%.
推定解放战力，55%
Get along, you two. Even adding both of your scores doesn't reach mine.
别吵架了 毕竟你们两个加起来还输给我
Jesus.
真是的
The more she improves, the more I realize how mediocre I am.
越努力锻炼，就越明白自己多平凡
Don't get distracted by her too much, Haruichi.
你还有时间关注前面的人吗？阳一
I've caught up to you in combat power.
我的战力和你一样了
AOI KAGURAGI 25%
（神乐木葵，25%）
I'm being attacked from above and below.
简直是腹背受敌啊
I'm going to overwrite your score once it's my turn.
换我去刷新自己的纪录了，葵
Kafka Hibino, six minutes and 39 seconds.
日比野卡夫卡，6分39秒
Estimated unleashed combat power is 1%.
推定解放战力，1%
All right!
太好了！
You see that, Kikoru? I finally turned my zero into a one!
看到了没？琪歌露 我终于从0变成1啦
-Don't come near me! -Look!
-别过来！ -你看！
Praise me!
快称赞我！
Why are you bragging about your 1%? I'm at 55!
为什么你这1%的 要跟55%的我炫耀啊？
-Kafka! -Yes, Vice Captain Hoshino!
-卡夫卡 -是，保科副队长
Keep this up and you'd never get promoted as an officer.
再这样下去，你没办法升格正式队员
-You'll be fired in three months! -What?
-三个月后就会被开除哦 -什么？
Old man.
大叔啊…
All right, run ten laps, and then we're done for the day!
好，今天就沿着外侧跑十圈后解散
What?
什么？
You complained, so now, it's 15 laps.
有意见的就跑15圈
-Go on! -Roger!
-快跑！ -了解
Looks like the newbies are pretty competitive.
那些新人的竞争意识很强烈呢
Apparently, they're competing and trying to improve,
在我没看见的地方
even when I'm not around.
似乎也会彼此竞争，努力精进呢
I'm so tired!
累死我了
Making us run laps in the end?
最后还外圈跑步
That Vice Captain is a demon.
副队长根本是恶魔
Your muscles are still underdeveloped, Reno!
你的肌肉还有待加强哦，雷诺
Yours are about the same as mine.
不是，你跟我差不多吧？
Our physical tests are similar, too.
体力测验结果也差不多
What? You're blind! Look closer at my biceps!
啥？给我看清楚这个上臂二头肌
They're just swollen for no reason.
那只是没用的肿块吧？
Seems like Reno is competitive. I didn't expect that.
没想到雷诺这么不服输呢
Don't be fighting over such stupid nonsense!
别因为这种无聊小事吵架
Maybe these adult muscles with real labor experience
看看我这身有劳动经验的成人肌肉
will shut you up!
乖乖闭嘴吧！
Wow! You're looking better, old man.
哇！大叔也挺结实…
SIGH, BOING!
（吐气）
Oh no, so close!
啊，不行，好可惜
That belly is unacceptable in the Defense Force!
他有防卫队员不该有的小腹
Don't be rude, Iharu-kun.
你很没礼貌，伊春
You assholes! Be prepared for when you're over 28!
你们这些家伙 过了28岁后就做好觉悟吧
It's getting better, okay?
这样已经比以前好了
Don't look at my belly. Let's arm wrestle!
不看肚子，用腕力一较高下吧！
-Bring it on, old man! -Challenge accepted.
-放马过来 -好啊
Lay down a towel here, and…
把毛巾放在这里，然后…
What's going on? It's louder than usual in here.
怎么了？今天还真热闹
What's wrong?
怎么了吗？
We're just a bunch of scrawny boys.
我们只是瘦巴巴的小男孩
As expected of a former Self-Defense officer.
真不愧是前自卫队军官
Muscles aren't important, right, Reno?
重点不是肌肉，对吧，雷诺？
This atmosphere brings me back.
好像很久没这样放松了
-Let's compete at tomorrow's training. -I won't lose!
-明天演习来比赛吧 -我不会输的
FRUITS MILK
（水果牛奶）
-Just as expected. -Right.
-理所当然咯 -就是说啊
Excuse us, ma'am!
失礼了！
It's all right. I'm almost done here.
没关系，快到交换的时间了
-Thank you, ma'am.
-谢谢
-Wow, I talked to her! -She's so cool.
-哇，讲到话了 -她好酷哦
Is your recovery going well?
身体康复了吗？
Yes, thanks to everyone's help.
是，多亏大家，已经没问题了
Just as I thought. She has well-balanced, trimmed muscles.
和想像的一样，她的肌肉精瘦结实
But that alone won't explain her overwhelming combat powers.
但这并不足以解释她的战斗力…
-What is it? -Oh, I'm sorry.
-怎么了？ -啊，抱歉
I was wondering how you get those muscles.
我在想要怎么练就那种肌肉…
I was wondering what your training routine was.
不，我想知道您是怎么锻炼的
Come next to me.
过来吧
I'll teach you the basics.
我教你基础
Here?
在这里吗？
Yes, please, ma'am!
拜托了
Hey, why did everyone join the Defense Force, anyways?
对了，大家为什么想加入防卫队？
If you want to know, you should tell us first.
要问别人，自己应该先说吧？
My answer is simple. Because of Captain Ashiro.
我就是为了亚白队长
Ever since she saved me in middle school,
自从国中被她救了之后
she's always been my idol!
我就一直很崇拜她
And you guys?
你们呢？
My family definitely influenced my decision, but I'm the same.
虽然有家庭因素，不过和你差不多
-I want to be like Captain Ashiro. -Same here.
-我的目标也是亚白队长 -我也是
Captain Ashiro's poster was so cool.
亚白队长的海报很酷吧？
That recent documentary was amazing, too.
之前的纪录片也很棒
Mina is really influential, huh?
米娜的影响力好强啊
She's the super hero of our generation.
毕竟她是我们世代的超级英雄嘛
-And you, old man? -Huh?
-那大叔呢？ -呃？
Well, as for me…
我啊…
What?
啥？
-Captain Ashiro is… -Your childhood friend?
-亚白队长… -是你的青梅竹马？
Well, yeah.
对啊
And you promised to be officers together?
还一起约好要成为队员？
A moving childhood memory?
类似“那天的承诺”之类的？
-I'll see you guys later. -Wait.
-我差不多该出去了 -站住
Tell us everything, all right?
你最好老实交代清楚
Well, the day Mina was born was a bright and sunny day.
那个…米娜出生的那天是大晴天
-Okay. -She always loved dried squid.
-哦 -她从小就爱吃鱿鱼丝
-That's surprising. -She raised the class pets in school.
-真意外 -小学的时候当过饲育股长
-Give us more! -Well, and then…
-多讲一点 -还有…
WOMEN
（女澡堂）
That was a nice bath!
洗得真舒服
Was there a mass murder here?
发生连续杀人事件吗？
Hey, Kikorun.
啊，琪歌露
They talked for too long in the bath and got heatstroke.
他们好像聊太久，泡到晕倒了
They were talking about Captain Ashiro.
听说是在聊亚白队长
Boys are so stupid!
男生都是笨蛋吗？
I don't have much time. I have to work twice as hard.
没时间了，我得比别人加倍努力
-You're hard at work, I see. -Huh?
-你很拼呢 -嗯？
-Vice Captain Hoshino! -Sleeping's part of the job.
-保科副队长！ -睡觉也是工作哦
I can't get fired from here.
因为我不能在这里就被开除
For Captain Ashiro?
为了亚白队长吗？
How did you know that?
你怎么知道？
You said so yourself, in the bath.
刚才在浴室你自己说的啊
No conversation held in this dormitory is kept a secret.
你最好记得 这个宿舍的对话都逃不过我的耳朵
So scary!
好恐怖！
I promised
我跟她约好了
to fight alongside her one day.
要和她并肩作战
I see. That sounds like you want to rob my position of Vice Captain from me.
哦，听起来很像 要从我这边抢走副队长的位置耶
That's not what I meant.
我没有那个意…
No.
不对
I'll work hard with that goal in mind.
我会抱持这种想法努力
Bring it on.
随时奉陪
Two hours. That's the max.
我只给你两小时
When leaving the room, turn off the lights and lock the door.
离开房间时，记得关灯上锁
I won't give up my position next to Captain Ashiro.
亚白队长旁的位置，我可不会让给你
-Thank you. -Also.
-非常感谢 -还有…
Be careful about being too friendly with the other officers.
跟其他队员打好关系，最好点到为止
In this job, you don't know what will happen to who.
毕竟这份工作 什么时候有人出事都不奇怪
Kaiju?
怪兽？
This isn't a drill, right?
这不是训练吧？
Speak of the devil.
说来就来
Let's go. It's your first mission.
走吧，你的初次任务
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰